<devicedata>
  <copyright>Copyright 2021 Wirepath Home Systems, LLC. All Rights Reserved.</copyright>
  <manufacturer>Control4</manufacturer>
  <name>Relay Garage Door Controller (OS2.9+)</name>
  <model>1-3 Relays</model>
  <creator>Control4</creator>
  <created>10/04/2016 10:30</created>
  <modified>04/02/2021 09:32 AM</modified>
  <version>11</version>
  <control>lua_gen</control>
  <driver>DriverWorks</driver>
  <auto_update>true</auto_update>
  <minimum_auto_update_version>1</minimum_auto_update_version>
  <minimum_os_version>2.9.0</minimum_os_version>
  <config>
    <script file="driver.lua"/>
    <documentation file="www/Documentation.rtf">
CONTROL4 DRIVER FOR GENERIC GARAGE DOORS CONTROLLED VIA RELAYS
Copyright 2021 Wirepath Home Systems, LLC. All Rights Reserved.


NOTE: THIS DRIVER REQUIRES CONTROL4 OS VERSION 2.9 OR LATER.

This driver provides an Experience Button which can be used to control garage doors via relays, and shows the current state of the garage door.

The driver is designed as an 'all in one' solution supporting garage doors controlled by 1, 2 or 3 relays.

If contact closures are available on the garage door and connected to the driver, they will be used to determine the status of the garage door.

NOTE: As this driver is an experience button, to view the garage door on Navigators, you must show the button, in System Design -&gt; Room Properties -&gt; Navigator Tab -&gt; Device Visibility and Display Order of desired category.  For example, you could choose to show the garage door experience button under Family Room Navigator's Security Menu.


----------------------------------
PROPERTIES

* Driver Version: Shows the version of the currently running driver.

* Debug Mode: Allows for showing Debug Messages on the Lua Output window.

* Number of Relays: Configuration for the number of relays used to control the garage door.

  - 1 Relay is used to either toggle the garage door state (like a garage door), or to set the requested state of the garage door (Open / Closed).

  - 2 Relays are used to set or trigger the state of the garage door (Open Relay, Close Relay).

  - 3 Relays are used to set or trigger the state of the garage door (Open Relay, Close Relay, Stop Relay).

* Relay Configuration: Relays are either configured as 'Hold' relays, where the relay stays activated to set the garage door state, or as 'Pulse' relays, where the relay is activated, and then deactivated, to set the garage door to a state.

* (Hold) Fail Safe Seconds: If 'Relay Configuration' is set to 'Hold', 'Stop' will be activated after Fail Safe Seconds have passed.  If Fail Safe is not required, set to 0.

If a stop relay is being used, it will be triggered.  If not, the 'Open' or 'Close' relay will be deactivated.

* (Pulse) Pulse Time milliseconds: The amount of time a relay will be pulsed.

* Invert Relays: If relays are opened to initiate the action, instead of closed, this property should be set to 'Yes'.

* Contact Status: Shows the contact sensors found attached to the driver.

* Contact Debounce milliseconds: Amount of time the driver will ignore additional state changes from a contact, to avoid 'contact bounce' causing the state to rapidly change.

* Invert Contacts: If contacts are opened to indicate the state, instead of closed, this property should be set to 'Yes'.

* Still Open Time: Amount of time (seconds) the door must be open after which the driver will fire the 'Still Open' event.

* Expected Open Time: Amount of time (in seconds) the door should take to open after which the driver will fire the 'Did Not Open' event.
  NOTE: Expected Open Time is hidden if both contact sensors are not connected.

* Expected Close Time: Amount of time (in seconds) the door should take to close after which the driver will fire the 'Did Not Close' event.
  NOTE: Expected Close Time is hidden if both contact sensors are not connected.

* Opened LED Color: Color of attached keypad buttons on 'Opened' garage door state.

* Closed LED Color: Color of attached keypad buttons on 'Closed' garage door state.

* Off LED Color: Color of attached Open/Close keypad buttons when not active (i.e. 'Open' button link when door closed and vice-versa).

* Partial Open LED Color: Color of attached keypad buttons on 'Partially Opened' garage door state.

* Unknown LED Color: Color of attached keypad buttons on 'Unknown' garage door state.


----------------------------------
SETUP

First select the number of relays that are used to control the garage doors.  Note if this property is changed then any existing relay connections will be unbound.

Then select if the relays are to be pulsed or held (latched) type.

Connect the relays to the 'Open/Close/Stop' relay connections in 'Connections -- Control/AV'.

If Hold relay configuration is selected then a failsafe time can be set for 2 and 3 relay devices which will open the relay (and close the stop relay if enabled) after the garage door should have closed.  If you do not require this feature set this value to 0.

If Pulse relay configuration is selected then you can set the time the relay should be pulsed for in milliseconds.

If the relays are inverted (i.e. they need to be opened to initiate the action) set invert relay to Yes.

For contact closure feedback, connect contact connections to the 'Closed Contact' (active on the door being fully closed) and 'Opened Contact' (active on the door being fully opened) contact sensor connections in 'Connections -- Control/AV'.

If contact closures are used, set the properties for debounce time and to invert the contact if desired.

If desired, set LED color choosers to show the status of the garage door when connected to a Control4 keypad.


----------------------------------
FEEDBACK

The Experience Button shows the current status of the garage door, based on either contact closures (if installed), or on the last requested state.

On Director restart, the driver will attempt to restore current state:

If Contacts are configured to determine the garage door state, the state of the garage door will be shown according to the contacts' state on restart.

If no contacts are configured, the driver will show garage door state based on the current relay state, with the following limitations:

* If Relay Configuration is set to 'Hold', the garage door state will be shown based on the 'Close' or 'Open' relays' state.  If the 'Stop' relay is active, the 'Unknown' state will be shown on the Experience Button.

* If Relay Configuration is set to 'Pulse', no state information is available, and the 'Unknown' state will be shown on the Experience Button.


----------------------------------
CONNECTIONS

Relay Connections are based on the 'Number of Relays' property.  Note that if the property is changed then any existing connections will be removed.

The 'Closed Contact' and 'Opened Contact' connections are optional but will be used for garage door status if connected.

Keypad button links are available to Open, Close or Toggle the garage door.


----------------------------------
EVENTS

* Selected: This event is fired when the Experience Button is selected in the Control4 UI.

* Opened: This event is fired when the garage door enters an opened state.

* Closed: This event is fired when the garage door enters a closed state.

* Partial: This event is fired when the garage door enters a partially opened state.  This event will only fire if the garage door status is determined by 2 installed contacts.

* Unknown: This event is fired when the garage door enters an unknown or incorrect state.  This event will only fire if the garage door status is determined by 2 installed contacts (and both contacts are 'active' simultaneously).

* Still Open: This event is fired when the door has been continuously open (not closed) longer than the 'Still Open Time' property.  Door must go from a Closed state to any other state (Open/Partially Open/Unknown) to start the timer.

* Did Not Open: This event is fired when the door was opening (opened contact activated and closed contact binding connected), but the door did not fully open within the 'Expected Open Time'.

* Did Not Close: This event is fired when the door was closing (closed contact activated and opened contact binding connected), but the door did not fully close within the 'Expected Close Time'.

NOTE: When no feedback contacts are installed, 'Opened' and 'Closed' events happen immediately upon the garage door relay activation.


----------------------------------
COMMANDS

* Select: This command causes the equivalent of the Experience Button being pressed on the UI.

* OPEN: Causes the garage door to open.

* CLOSE: Causes the garage door to close.

* STOP: Causes the garage door to stop, assuming the relay setup and configuration supports stop.


----------------------------------
VARIABLES

* STATE: This variable holds the garage door state.  Valid values include: 'Opened', 'Closed', 'Partial', and 'Unknown'.


----------------------------------
SUPPORT

For support on this driver please contact Control4 technical support or your local Control4 distributor.


----------------------------------
CHANGELOG

Version 1: Initial Release Version.

Version 5: Added 'Still Open' timer and event, changed so that single relay toggle configuration always sends toggle, regardless of current state.

Version 6: Fixed Defect #39360 - if gate is in a known state and command for that state is sent, it causes pulse getting driver into the wrong state.

Version 7: Fixed Defect #41282 - Pulse times are not being used, driver always pulses for 500ms, increased maximum pulse time to 60 seconds..

Version 8, 9: Refresh of Driver Icons to new icon style.

Version 10: Updated RecordHistory with Categories and Subcategories to match Contact/Relay drivers.

Version 11: Added 'Did Not Open' and 'Did Not Close' events.

</documentation>
    <conditionals>
      <conditional>
        <id>1</id>
        <name>State</name>
        <type>LIST</type>
        <condition_statement>State</condition_statement>
        <description>NAME State is LOGIC STRING</description>
        <items>
          <item>Opened</item>
          <item>Closed</item>
          <item>Partially Open</item>
          <item>Unknown</item>
        </items>
      </conditional>
    </conditionals>
    <properties>
      <property>
        <name>Driver Version</name>
        <default/>
        <type>STRING</type>
        <readonly>true</readonly>
      </property>
      <property>
        <name>Debug Mode</name>
        <type>LIST</type>
        <items>
          <item>Off</item>
          <item>On</item>
        </items>
        <default>Off</default>
        <readonly>false</readonly>
      </property>
      <property>
        <name>Control Method</name>
        <type>LIST</type>
        <items>
          <item>Relay</item>
          <item>HomeKit</item>
        </items>
        <default>Relay</default>
        <readonly>false</readonly>
      </property>
      <property>
        <name>Accessory AID</name>
        <type>STRING</type>
        <default>1</default>
        <readonly>false</readonly>
      </property>
      <property>
        <name>Icon Set</name>
        <type>LIST</type>
        <items>
          <item>Light</item>
          <item>Dark</item>
        </items>
        <default>Light</default>
        <readonly>false</readonly>
        <tooltip>Configuration for the 'Light' or 'Dark' garage door icon set.</tooltip>
      </property>
      <property>
        <name>Number of Relays</name>
        <type>LIST</type>
        <items>
          <item>1</item>
          <item>2</item>
          <item>3</item>
        </items>
        <default>1</default>
        <readonly>false</readonly>
        <tooltip>Configuration for the number of relays used to control the garage door.</tooltip>
      </property>
      <property>
        <name>Relay Configuration</name>
        <type>LIST</type>
        <items>
          <item>Hold</item>
          <item>Pulse</item>
        </items>
        <default>Pulse</default>
        <readonly>false</readonly>
        <tooltip>Relays are either configured as 'Hold' relays, where the relay stays activated to set the door state, or as 'Pulse' relays, where the relay is activated, and then deactivated, to set the door to a state.</tooltip>
      </property>
      <property>
        <name>Fail Safe Seconds</name>
        <type>RANGED_INTEGER</type>
        <readonly>false</readonly>
        <default>0</default>
        <minimum>0</minimum>
        <maximum>600</maximum>
        <tooltip>If 'Relay Configuration' is set to 'Hold', 'Stop' will be activated after Fail Safe Seconds have passed.  If Fail Safe is not required, set to 0. (default 0)</tooltip>
      </property>
      <property>
        <name>Open/Toggle Relay Pulse Time (ms)</name>
        <type>RANGED_INTEGER</type>
        <readonly>false</readonly>
        <default>500</default>
        <minimum>50</minimum>
        <maximum>60000</maximum>
        <tooltip>The amount of time the open/toggle relay will be pulsed. (default 500)</tooltip>
      </property>
      <property>
        <name>Invert Open/Toggle Relay</name>
        <type>LIST</type>
        <items>
          <item>Yes</item>
          <item>No</item>
        </items>
        <default>No</default>
        <readonly>false</readonly>
        <tooltip>If open/toggle relay is opened to initiate an action, instead of closed, set this property to 'Yes'. (default 'No')</tooltip>
      </property>
      <property>
        <name>Close Relay Pulse Time (ms)</name>
        <type>RANGED_INTEGER</type>
        <readonly>false</readonly>
        <default>500</default>
        <minimum>50</minimum>
        <maximum>60000</maximum>
        <tooltip>The amount of time the close relay will be pulsed. (default 500)</tooltip>
      </property>
      <property>
        <name>Invert Close Relay</name>
        <type>LIST</type>
        <items>
          <item>Yes</item>
          <item>No</item>
        </items>
        <default>No</default>
        <readonly>false</readonly>
        <tooltip>If close relay is opened to initiate an action, instead of closed, set this property to 'Yes'. (default 'No')</tooltip>
      </property>
      <property>
        <name>Stop Relay Pulse Time (ms)</name>
        <type>RANGED_INTEGER</type>
        <readonly>false</readonly>
        <default>500</default>
        <minimum>50</minimum>
        <maximum>60000</maximum>
        <tooltip>The amount of time the stop relay will be pulsed. (default 500)</tooltip>
      </property>
      <property>
        <name>Invert Stop Relay</name>
        <type>LIST</type>
        <items>
          <item>Yes</item>
          <item>No</item>
        </items>
        <default>No</default>
        <readonly>false</readonly>
        <tooltip>If stop relay is opened to initiate an action, instead of closed, set this property to 'Yes'. (default 'No')</tooltip>
      </property>
      <property>
        <name>Contact Status</name>
        <default/>
        <type>STRING</type>
        <readonly>true</readonly>
        <tooltip>Shows the contact sensors found attached to the driver.</tooltip>
      </property>
      <property>
        <name>Opened Contact Debounce (ms)</name>
        <type>RANGED_INTEGER</type>
        <readonly>false</readonly>
        <default>250</default>
        <minimum>1</minimum>
        <maximum>1000</maximum>
        <tooltip>Amount of time the driver will ignore additional state changes from the 'opened' contact, to avoid 'contact bounce' causing the state to rapidly change. (default 250)</tooltip>
      </property>
      <property>
        <name>Invert Opened Contact</name>
        <type>LIST</type>
        <items>
          <item>Yes</item>
          <item>No</item>
        </items>
        <default>No</default>
        <readonly>false</readonly>
        <tooltip>If the opened contact is opened to indicate the state, instead of closed, set this property to 'Yes'. (default 'No')</tooltip>
      </property>
      <property>
        <name>Closed Contact Debounce (ms)</name>
        <type>RANGED_INTEGER</type>
        <readonly>false</readonly>
        <default>250</default>
        <minimum>1</minimum>
        <maximum>1000</maximum>
        <tooltip>Amount of time the driver will ignore additional state changes from the 'closed' contact, to avoid 'contact bounce' causing the state to rapidly change. (default 250)</tooltip>
      </property>
      <property>
        <name>Invert Closed Contact</name>
        <type>LIST</type>
        <items>
          <item>Yes</item>
          <item>No</item>
        </items>
        <default>No</default>
        <readonly>false</readonly>
        <tooltip>If the closed contact is opened to indicate the state, instead of closed, set this property to 'Yes'. (default 'No')</tooltip>
      </property>
      <property>
        <name>Still Open Time (s)</name>
        <type>RANGED_INTEGER</type>
        <readonly>false</readonly>
        <default>60</default>
        <minimum>5</minimum>
        <maximum>3600</maximum>
        <tooltip>Amount of time (in seconds) the door must be open after which the driver will fire the 'Still Open' event. (default 60)</tooltip>
      </property>
      <property>
        <name>Expected Open Time (s)</name>
        <type>RANGED_INTEGER</type>
        <readonly>false</readonly>
        <default>60</default>
        <minimum>5</minimum>
        <maximum>3600</maximum>
        <tooltip>Amount of time (in seconds) the door should take to open after which the driver will fire the 'Did Not Open' event. (default 60)</tooltip>
      </property>
      <property>
        <name>Expected Close Time (s)</name>
        <type>RANGED_INTEGER</type>
        <readonly>false</readonly>
        <default>60</default>
        <minimum>5</minimum>
        <maximum>3600</maximum>
        <tooltip>Amount of time (in seconds) the door should take to close after which the driver will fire the 'Did Not Close' event. (default 60)</tooltip>
      </property>
      <property>
        <name>Opened LED Color</name>
        <type>COLOR_SELECTOR</type>
        <default>0,200,0</default>
        <readonly>false</readonly>
        <tooltip>Color of attached keypad buttons on 'Opened' garage door state.</tooltip>
      </property>
      <property>
        <name>Closed LED Color</name>
        <type>COLOR_SELECTOR</type>
        <default>200,0,0</default>
        <readonly>false</readonly>
        <tooltip>Color of attached keypad buttons on 'Closed' garage door state.</tooltip>
      </property>
      <property>
        <name>Off LED Color</name>
        <type>COLOR_SELECTOR</type>
        <default>0,0,200</default>
        <readonly>false</readonly>
        <tooltip>Color of attached Open/Close keypad buttons when not active (i.e. 'Open' button link when door closed and vice-versa).</tooltip>
      </property>
      <property>
        <name>Partial Open LED Color</name>
        <type>COLOR_SELECTOR</type>
        <default>200,200,0</default>
        <readonly>false</readonly>
        <tooltip>Color of attached keypad buttons on 'Partially Opened' garage door state.</tooltip>
      </property>
      <property>
        <name>Unknown LED Color</name>
        <type>COLOR_SELECTOR</type>
        <default>0,0,0</default>
        <readonly>false</readonly>
        <tooltip>Color of attached keypad buttons on 'Unknown' garage door state.</tooltip>
      </property>
    </properties>
    <commands>
      <command>
        <name>OPEN</name>
        <description>Open NAME</description>
      </command>
      <command>
        <name>CLOSE</name>
        <description>Close NAME</description>
      </command>
      <command>
        <name>STOP</name>
        <description>Stop NAME</description>
      </command>
    </commands>
    <actions>
      <action>
        <name>Open Garage Door</name>
        <command>OPEN</command>
      </action>
      <action>
        <name>Close Garage Door</name>
        <command>CLOSE</command>
      </action>
      <action>
        <name>Stop Garage Door</name>
        <command>STOP</command>
      </action>
      <action>
        <name>Reset LED Colors to Project Defaults</name>
        <command>RESET_COLORS</command>
      </action>
    </actions>
  </config>
  <events>
    <event>
      <id>1</id>
      <name>Opened</name>
      <description>When the NAME Garage Door is Opened</description>
    </event>
    <event>
      <id>2</id>
      <name>Closed</name>
      <description>When the NAME Garage Door is Closed</description>
    </event>
    <event>
      <id>3</id>
      <name>Partial</name>
      <description>When the NAME Garage Door is Partially Opened</description>
    </event>
    <event>
      <id>4</id>
      <name>Unknown</name>
      <description>When the NAME Garage Door is in an Unknown State</description>
    </event>
    <event>
      <id>5</id>
      <name>Still Open</name>
      <description>When the NAME Door has been open longer than the 'Still Open Time' property time</description>
    </event>
    <event>
      <id>6</id>
      <name>Did Not Open</name>
      <description>When the NAME Door was opening, but did not fully open before the 'Expected Open Time' property</description>
    </event>
    <event>
      <id>7</id>
      <name>Did Not Close</name>
      <description>When the NAME Door was closing, but did not fully close before the 'Expected Close Time' property</description>
    </event>
  </events>
  <capabilities>
    <DeviceType>Garage Door</DeviceType>
    <navigator_display_option proxybindingid="5001">
      <display_icons>
        <Icon width="70" height="70">controller://driver/garagedoor_relay_control/icons/device/garage_closed/experience_70.png</Icon>
        <Icon width="90" height="90">controller://driver/garagedoor_relay_control/icons/device/garage_closed/experience_90.png</Icon>
        <Icon width="300" height="300">controller://driver/garagedoor_relay_control/icons/device/garage_closed/experience_300.png</Icon>
        <Icon width="512" height="512">controller://driver/garagedoor_relay_control/icons/device/garage_closed/experience_512.png</Icon>
        <Icon width="1024" height="1024">controller://driver/garagedoor_relay_control/icons/device/garage_closed/experience_1024.png</Icon>
        <state id="Opened_Light">
          <Icon width="70" height="70">controller://driver/garagedoor_relay_control/icons/device/garage_open/experience_70.png</Icon>
          <Icon width="90" height="90">controller://driver/garagedoor_relay_control/icons/device/garage_open/experience_90.png</Icon>
          <Icon width="300" height="300">controller://driver/garagedoor_relay_control/icons/device/garage_open/experience_300.png</Icon>
          <Icon width="512" height="512">controller://driver/garagedoor_relay_control/icons/device/garage_open/experience_512.png</Icon>
          <Icon width="1024" height="1024">controller://driver/garagedoor_relay_control/icons/device/garage_open/experience_1024.png</Icon>
        </state>
        <state id="Closed_Light">
          <Icon width="70" height="70">controller://driver/garagedoor_relay_control/icons/device/garage_closed/experience_70.png</Icon>
          <Icon width="90" height="90">controller://driver/garagedoor_relay_control/icons/device/garage_closed/experience_90.png</Icon>
          <Icon width="300" height="300">controller://driver/garagedoor_relay_control/icons/device/garage_closed/experience_300.png</Icon>
          <Icon width="512" height="512">controller://driver/garagedoor_relay_control/icons/device/garage_closed/experience_512.png</Icon>
          <Icon width="1024" height="1024">controller://driver/garagedoor_relay_control/icons/device/garage_closed/experience_1024.png</Icon>
        </state>
        <state id="Partial_Light">
          <Icon width="70" height="70">controller://driver/garagedoor_relay_control/icons/device/garage_between/experience_70.png</Icon>
          <Icon width="90" height="90">controller://driver/garagedoor_relay_control/icons/device/garage_between/experience_90.png</Icon>
          <Icon width="300" height="300">controller://driver/garagedoor_relay_control/icons/device/garage_between/experience_300.png</Icon>
          <Icon width="512" height="512">controller://driver/garagedoor_relay_control/icons/device/garage_between/experience_512.png</Icon>
          <Icon width="1024" height="1024">controller://driver/garagedoor_relay_control/icons/device/garage_between/experience_1024.png</Icon>
        </state>
        <state id="Unknown_Light">
          <Icon width="70" height="70">controller://driver/garagedoor_relay_control/icons/device/garage_unknown/experience_70.png</Icon>
          <Icon width="90" height="90">controller://driver/garagedoor_relay_control/icons/device/garage_unknown/experience_90.png</Icon>
          <Icon width="300" height="300">controller://driver/garagedoor_relay_control/icons/device/garage_unknown/experience_300.png</Icon>
          <Icon width="512" height="512">controller://driver/garagedoor_relay_control/icons/device/garage_unknown/experience_512.png</Icon>
          <Icon width="1024" height="1024">controller://driver/garagedoor_relay_control/icons/device/garage_unknown/experience_1024.png</Icon>
        </state>
        <state id="Opened_Dark">
          <Icon width="70" height="70">controller://driver/garagedoor_relay_control/icons/device/garage_open_alt/experience_70.png</Icon>
          <Icon width="90" height="90">controller://driver/garagedoor_relay_control/icons/device/garage_open_alt/experience_90.png</Icon>
          <Icon width="300" height="300">controller://driver/garagedoor_relay_control/icons/device/garage_open_alt/experience_300.png</Icon>
          <Icon width="512" height="512">controller://driver/garagedoor_relay_control/icons/device/garage_open_alt/experience_512.png</Icon>
          <Icon width="1024" height="1024">controller://driver/garagedoor_relay_control/icons/device/garage_open_alt/experience_1024.png</Icon>
        </state>
        <state id="Closed_Dark">
          <Icon width="70" height="70">controller://driver/garagedoor_relay_control/icons/device/garage_closed_alt/experience_70.png</Icon>
          <Icon width="90" height="90">controller://driver/garagedoor_relay_control/icons/device/garage_closed_alt/experience_90.png</Icon>
          <Icon width="300" height="300">controller://driver/garagedoor_relay_control/icons/device/garage_closed_alt/experience_300.png</Icon>
          <Icon width="512" height="512">controller://driver/garagedoor_relay_control/icons/device/garage_closed_alt/experience_512.png</Icon>
          <Icon width="1024" height="1024">controller://driver/garagedoor_relay_control/icons/device/garage_closed_alt/experience_1024.png</Icon>
        </state>
        <state id="Partial_Dark">
          <Icon width="70" height="70">controller://driver/garagedoor_relay_control/icons/device/garage_between_alt/experience_70.png</Icon>
          <Icon width="90" height="90">controller://driver/garagedoor_relay_control/icons/device/garage_between_alt/experience_90.png</Icon>
          <Icon width="300" height="300">controller://driver/garagedoor_relay_control/icons/device/garage_between_alt/experience_300.png</Icon>
          <Icon width="512" height="512">controller://driver/garagedoor_relay_control/icons/device/garage_between_alt/experience_512.png</Icon>
          <Icon width="1024" height="1024">controller://driver/garagedoor_relay_control/icons/device/garage_between_alt/experience_1024.png</Icon>
        </state>
        <state id="Unknown_Dark">
          <Icon width="70" height="70">controller://driver/garagedoor_relay_control/icons/device/garage_unknown_alt/experience_70.png</Icon>
          <Icon width="90" height="90">controller://driver/garagedoor_relay_control/icons/device/garage_unknown_alt/experience_90.png</Icon>
          <Icon width="300" height="300">controller://driver/garagedoor_relay_control/icons/device/garage_unknown_alt/experience_300.png</Icon>
          <Icon width="512" height="512">controller://driver/garagedoor_relay_control/icons/device/garage_unknown_alt/experience_512.png</Icon>
          <Icon width="1024" height="1024">controller://driver/garagedoor_relay_control/icons/device/garage_unknown_alt/experience_1024.png</Icon>
        </state>
      </display_icons>
    </navigator_display_option>
  </capabilities>
  <composer_categories>
    <category>Motorization</category>
  </composer_categories>
  <proxies>
    <proxy proxybindingid="5001" name="Garage Door" image_source="c4z" large_image="icons/device_lg.png" small_image="icons/device_sm.png">uibutton</proxy>
  </proxies>
  <connections>
    <connection>
      <id>5001</id>
      <facing>6</facing>
      <connectionname>UIBUTTON</connectionname>
      <type>2</type>
      <consumer>False</consumer>
      <audiosource>False</audiosource>
      <videosource>False</videosource>
      <linelevel>False</linelevel>
      <classes>
        <class>
          <classname>UIBUTTON</classname>
        </class>
      </classes>
    </connection>
    <connection>
      <id>4</id>
      <facing>6</facing>
      <connectionname>Closed Contact</connectionname>
      <type>1</type>
      <consumer>True</consumer>
      <audiosource>False</audiosource>
      <videosource>False</videosource>
      <linelevel>True</linelevel>
      <classes>
        <class>
          <classname>CONTACT_SENSOR</classname>
        </class>
      </classes>
    </connection>
    <connection>
      <id>5</id>
      <facing>6</facing>
      <connectionname>Opened Contact</connectionname>
      <type>1</type>
      <consumer>True</consumer>
      <audiosource>False</audiosource>
      <videosource>False</videosource>
      <linelevel>True</linelevel>
      <classes>
        <class>
          <classname>CONTACT_SENSOR</classname>
        </class>
      </classes>
    </connection>
    <connection>
      <id>500</id>
      <facing>6</facing>
      <connectionname>Toggle</connectionname>
      <type>1</type>
      <consumer>False</consumer>
      <audiosource>False</audiosource>
      <videosource>False</videosource>
      <linelevel>False</linelevel>
      <classes>
        <class>
          <classname>BUTTON_LINK</classname>
          <autobind>False</autobind>
        </class>
      </classes>
      <hidden>False</hidden>
    </connection>
    <connection>
      <id>501</id>
      <facing>6</facing>
      <connectionname>Open</connectionname>
      <type>1</type>
      <consumer>False</consumer>
      <audiosource>False</audiosource>
      <videosource>False</videosource>
      <linelevel>False</linelevel>
      <classes>
        <class>
          <classname>BUTTON_LINK</classname>
          <autobind>False</autobind>
        </class>
      </classes>
      <hidden>False</hidden>
    </connection>
    <connection>
      <id>502</id>
      <facing>6</facing>
      <connectionname>Close</connectionname>
      <type>1</type>
      <consumer>False</consumer>
      <audiosource>False</audiosource>
      <videosource>False</videosource>
      <linelevel>False</linelevel>
      <classes>
        <class>
          <classname>BUTTON_LINK</classname>
          <autobind>False</autobind>
        </class>
      </classes>
      <hidden>False</hidden>
    </connection>
    <connection>
      <id>999</id>
      <facing>1</facing>
      <connectionname>HomeKit Hub</connectionname>
      <type>1</type>
      <consumer>True</consumer>
      <audiosource>False</audiosource>
      <videosource>False</videosource>
      <linelevel>False</linelevel>
      <classes>
        <class>
          <classname>HOMEKIT_DEVICE</classname>
          <autobind>True</autobind>
        </class>
      </classes>
    </connection>
  </connections>
</devicedata>
